https://kaveeshakavindi.github.io/Kaveesha_Portfolio/

KAVEESHA FERNANDO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

+94 71 694 5834

kaveeshafernando3@gmail.com

• 428/4, Circular Rd, Panadura 12500, Sri Lanka

in Kaveesha Fernando

Bē kaveeshafernand

kaveeshakavindi

@kaveesha.20210431

https://kaveeshakavindi.github.io/Kaveesha_Portfolio/



PROFILE SUMMARY

Out of the box thinking Software Engineer with one year of industry experience as a mobile engineering intern at Axiata Digital Labs, excelled in UI/UX designing and full-stack development. Began my journey with learning Java, sparking a passion for UI/UX design. Mastered all four MERN stack components along with Java, Python and Kotlin, solidifying my skills as a full-stack developer. Spearheaded the Software Development Group Project of building iDerm24: an android app that identifies skin diseases. Worked as Media Head and IT and Marketing Director at institute clubs and club based projects.

SKILLS

BACK-END DEVELOPMENT

Programming Languages:

- Node.js (JavaScript/TypeScript)
- Java
- Python

Server-Side Frameworks:

• Express.js (Node.js)

Database Management:

- SQL Databases (MySQL)
- NoSQL Databases (MongoDB)

APIs (Application Programming Interfaces):

RESTful APIs

MOBILE APP DEVELOPMENT

Programming Languages:

- Java/Kotlin (Android)
- Dart (Flutter)
- JavaScript/TypeScript (React Native)

Cross-Platform Development:

- React Native
- Flutter

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Programming Languages:

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

Frameworks and Libraries:

React.js

IDES AND SOFTWARES

Programming:

- Visual Studio Code
- Android Studio
- IntelliJ
- XCODE

UI/UX Designing:

- Figma
- Adobe XD

Graphic Designing:

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Procreate

EDUCATION

Senior Young Learners English Course

2014-2016

British Council, Sri Lanka

School Education

2007-2020

Sri Sumangala Girls' School

GCE Ordinary Level Examination

2017

Sri Sumangala Girls' School

8As, 1B

GCE Advanced Level Examination

2020

Sri Sumangala Girls' School

Combined Mathematics (Pure + Applied)

– C

Physics Chemistry

- C

BEng. Software Engineering Undergraduate

2021- Present

Informatics Institute of Technology

Professional Certificate in Digital Graphic

Design and 3D Animation

Informatics Institute of Technology

2022

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Engineering Intern

2023-2024

Axiata Digital Labs

FEATURED PROJECTS

Hospital Management System Java

Developed a user-friendly Java-based Hospital Management System with a focus on intuitive GUI design, emphasizing functionalities such as appointment scheduling, doctor addition, and overall system management.

Portfolio Website React | Figma

Developed a user-friendly and responsive portfolio website using React.js to showcase professional accomplishments and skills.

Meal App Kotlin | Figma

Developed a Kotlin-based meal app, utilizing the MealDB API, implementing CRUD functionalities with HTTP methods, and integrating a local array list for data management, coupled with a user-friendly interface designed using Figma.

CraftMasters React Native | Figma

Developed entire React Native app from UI design in Figma, featuring a user-friendly horizontally scrollable tab bar with seamless dark and light theme integration using React Native context.

VOLUNTEERING

IT and Marketing Directer 2021-2022

Leo Club of IIT

Secretary 2022–2023

Leo Club of IIT

Media Head October - 2023

Open Hack (Inter-uni Hackathon)

Zone Director 2023-Present

Leo District 306A1

REFERENCES

Sevwandi Liyanage

Associate Tech Lead Software Engineering at Axiata Digital Labs

\(+94 777332927

sevwandi.liyanage@axiatadigitallabs.com

Sulochana Rupasinghe

Lecturer at Informatics Institute of Technology

+94 768209889

sulochana.r@iit.ac.lk